欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内 字幕广告招租 商业合作Q:1585235535
《犯罪心理：演变》前情提要
Previously on"Criminal Minds: Evolution"...灬
看来几十年来这里一直有个杀手在活动
Lewis: Looks like there's been an active killer up here
一些实验室的技本人员
for decades. Some of the lab techs
开始称这个不明嫌犯为六眼杀蛛
are starting to call this UnSub Sicarius.
不明嫌犯聚集了一众追随者
Prentiss: The UnSub gathered followers
他正在启用他们
that he's now activating.
这是一个犯罪网络
This is a network.
你和丽贝卡肯定在一起了
You and Rebecca are so a thing.
-我正在接受审查 -我们能回家再谈吗
Rebecca: I'm under review. Can we talk about this at home?
我不回家了
I'm not going home.
泰勒·格林是我们1年来遇到的
Rossi: Tyler Green is our only lead
最神秘杀手的唯一线索
on the most elusive killer in 15 years.
你不是加入了那个网络 你渗透进去了
You didn't join that network. You infiltrated it.
他是我的线人
He's my informant.
你必须和他断联
You have to break it off with him.
伊莱亚斯·沃伊特 他知道我们快查到了
Elias Voit. He knows we're getting close,
他会再次溜走的
and he'll try to slip away again.
死亡人数已达52人 我是不会冒这个险的
Your body count is up to 52. I'm not taking any chances.
沃伊特正在直播 马上发给你们
Garcia: Voit is live streaming. Sharing it now.
我们看到了
Prentiss: We see it.
救命 救命
Helpl Help!
大卫
Dave.
我是贝利副局长
This is Deputy Director Bailey.
准备好做交易了吗
Ready to make a deal?
我知道你不是管事的
I know you're not the man in charge,
但你绝对是个喜欢金星的人
but you're definitely the one who likes the gold star.
只有两个人知道这件事
There's only two people who know about it
你知我知
Only you and me.
我有权保持沉默 我所说的一切
I have the right to remain silent. Anything I say
都将成为呈堂证供
can and will be used against me in a court of law.
什么是金星啊
What the hell is Gold Star?
司法部内部有问题
There are issues within the DOJ
我不能也不会跟你说
that I cannot and I will not talk to you about.
哪怕是为了救罗西的命也不能吗
Even to save Rossi's life?
-我在这儿 -大卫
Rossi: I m here! Dave? l
我还活着
I'm alive!
我们只是想弄清楚
We're just trying to understand
贝利那边到底什么情况
what happened out there with Bailey.
他的自尊心占了上风
His ego got the best of him.
这肯定是部分原因
That's definitely part of it.
报告里缺了什么
What was not in the report?
金星
Gold Star.
整得就像在比赛一样
It's like there's a contest back there.
比谁能做出世界上最难喝的咖啡
Who can make the world's shittiest coffee?
你应该少喝点咖啡
You should ease up on that.
你居然也会说这话
Since when?
医生说酸性饮食在侵蚀我的牙齿
Doctor said acid's eating my teeth.
那你现在喜欢喝什么
Then what's your poison?
茉莉花茶加蜂蜜
Jasmine tea and honey.
现在我是什么都见识过了
Now Ive seen everything.
-美味 -以后都不能喝咖啡和酒了
Delicious. No more coffee. No more alcohol.
什么鬼
What the hell?
贝托利 怎么回事
Bertoli, what happened?
天哪 那是枪伤
Klein: Oh my God. That's a gunshot wound.
趴在地上
On the ground now.
我的老天奶啊
Sweet mother of God.
到底怎么回事 贝托利
What the hell happened, Bertoli?
天啊
Oh, my God.
说话 快说话啊
Talk. Talk to us.
叫医护人员过来
Get the medics in herel
这特么啥情况
What the hell?
你认为是他干的
You think he did it?
他是我们的人 不可能
Klein: He's one of ours. Not a chance.
不可能的 对吧
No way. I mean, right?
克肖刚把这些发过来
Kershaw just sent these over.
我从没见过这样的情况
I've never seen anything like this.
我见过
Prentiss: I have.
你是哪位
Who are you?
特别检察官艾米丽·普兰蒂斯 联调局行为分析小组
SSA Emily Prentiss. FBI's Behavioral Analysis Unit.
我们没有邀请你来
We didn't invite you in.
你们检查过他的枪吗
Have you checked his gun?
枪膛里有一颗子弹
There is a bullet in the chamber
上面有激光刻的一颗五角星
with a five- pointed star laser- etched onto it.
这就是凶手的名片
It's our killer's calling card.
真正的凶手
The realkiller.
然后呢 你能破案吗
Now what? You're gonna solve this?
就一个人破吗
AlI by yourself?
人们说陈年旧事可以被埋葬
Prentiss: It's wrong what they say about the past,
然而我终于明白这是骗人的
I've learned, about how you can bury it.
因为往事总会想办法爬出来
Because the, past claws its way out. "
摘自卡勒德·胡赛尼《追风筝的人》
Khaled Hosseini.
不 不 你的脸
No! Nol Your facel
-太棒了 -哦 你什么毛病
That was great Oh, what is wrong with you?
我可以的 真的 真的
I got it. Seriously. Seriously.
I got it Seriously. Seriously.
不 真的 嗯 挺好的
嗯 但是
Um, but
-你怎么了 -我怎么了
AISHA TYLER What is wrong with you? What is wrong with me? －
-嗯 -那她呢
Yes. What about her?
-哦 我吗 -嗯
Oh, mine? Yeah.
我可能会把这 我说的话这纹在身上了
I might have that what I said tattooed to my body.
-我赌你不敢 我 -你怎么敢赌我敢不敢
嗯 塔拉 我觉得你对我们有所隐瞒
Okay, uh, Tara, I feel like you've been holding out on us.
-你手里有什么 -天呐
What do you got? Oh, God.
发明这个游戏的人真的很过分
你是想说过分天才吧
Truly inventive, you meant to say.
我们下次在我家玩
We are doing this at my place next time
因为我要选玩儿什么
NICOLE PACENT because I am picking the game.
哦 别这样你呗在是在浪费时间 快点
哦 别这样 你现在是在浪费时间 快点
Oh, come on. You are wasting time right now. Let's go.
敬启者
"To whom it may concern. "
致以诚挚的歉意 飞盘高尔夫部
with sincere apologies, the Department of Frisbee Golf
将不再参加
will no longer participate
大坨粪便
KITTY DORIS- BATES with...giant turds.
with...giant turds.
你平时说话明明比这个污
Oh. With that sailor mouth?
我 我很失望
Director of Photography
ANTHONY VIETROram1axtalyukppointed
我 我很失望
I am...I am very disappointed.
很明显我的牌很烂
I clearly had a sucky hand.
牌很烂啊 那我们可以发挥一下
Oh, a sucky hand. We can do something with sucky hand.
这不就是 烂牌有烂牌的打法
There you go. You can do a lot with a sucky hand.
好吧 不幸的是
Okay, unfortunately,
卢克还在学习什么叫阴吹
Consulting Producer
MATTHEW LAU Luke is still in the lead with queef lessons.
好了 好了
Alright, come on
还没轮到大卫呢
Dave hasn't gone yet.
非得轮到我吗
Rossi: If I must.
-是的 没错 -好吧
Co- Executive Producer Giai coeLLo BANNd
敬启者 致以诚挚的歉意
To whom it may concern, with sincere apologies,
老男人
the department of
Executive Producer
GLENN KERSHAW old man woodies..."
硬棍儿部门
Executive Producer
GLENN KERSHAW old man woodies..."
硬棍儿部门
继续啊
Oh. Yes?
Executive Producer
BREEN FRAZIER "...will no longer participate with
将不再参与
"...will no longer participate with.
-后庭之事 -好耶
that ass. Yes!
Executive Producer
MARK GORDON And we have a winner.
胜负已分
-好的 -好的
Oh. Oh. Okay.
Executive Producer
Ah! That's alright To Dave.
-很好 -敬大卫
-敬大卫 -敬大卫 你是真挺有想法
To Dave. To Dave. That was solid of you.
哦 谢谢你能过来
Oh, thank you for coming. Oh.
这样挺好的
This was good.
你气色不错
You seem good.
生日快乐 孩子
Happy birthday, kid. Okay.
-明天见 -嘿 听着
See you tomorrow. Hey, listen, I know
我知道我们老是唠叨同一句话
we're starting to sound like a broken record,
但你明天不必来上班
but there's no pressure on you to come in tomorrow.
你攒下的假期比我们所有人都多
I mean, you've got more vacation time saved up than all of us.
主要是我闹不下来
It's time. Idle hands.
好吧 好吧 晚安
Alright, alright. Sleep well.
对
Yeah.
他看起来还不错
He seems good.
-有点太不错了 不是吗 -也许是在过渡弥补
-有点太不错了 不是吗 -也许是在过度弥补
Too good, right? Like, maybe overcompensating
被伊莱亚斯·沃伊特绑架的创伤
for the trauma of being abducted by Elias Voit?
我们应该吃点蛋糕
We should eat some cake.
对 对
Yeah. Yeah.
很多人对联调局副局长
News anchor: Many are unsatisfied
道格拉斯·贝利
with the answers, or lack thereof,
在加州伯尼市
regarding the fatal shooting
被枪杀一案的官方回复并不满意
of FBI Deputy Director Douglas Bailey in Burney, California.
哦 阴谋论正在酝酿
Ohh. Conspiracy theories are brewing.
还好这周你没啥压力
Good thing there's no pressure on you this week.
下周也没有
Or next.
你所做的一切
This whole thing you do,
都是在递减收益 真的
it's diminishing returns, really.
我的意思是 当然 你可能会抓到一个
I mean, sure, you may catch one,
但外面还有多少个呢
but how many more are still out there?
他们都不如我厉害噢
None of them will ever be as good as me.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你还好吗
Hey, you good?
还好 我只是在热车
Oh, y- yeah, I'm just warming up.
是啊 外面很冷的 伙计
Yeah, it's cold out here, man.
嗯 确实 开车小心点 好吗
Yeah, it sure is. Drive safe, huh?
-你也是 -嗯
You, too. Okay.
-晚安 -晚安
Good night. Good night.
别看了
Put it away.
什么 别 什么啊
What- - No What?
我只是在看我的短信
I'mjust checking my text messages.
得了吧
Come on.
你清楚我知道那是泰勒发的短信 你知道我怎么知道的吗
You know I know it's Tyler. And do you know how I know?
因为你一脸呆滞的表情
Because you get this glazed look over your face.
好了 真的没什么的
Oh, come on. It's really nothing.
他只是说生日快乐
He just said happy birthday.
还有派对的表情符号和一个小蛋糕
And then he put the party face emoji and a cupcake.
还有一本书
And a book?
那是什么意思 我都不想知道
The hell is that about? I- I don't even want to know.
-你不会想知道的 -我不想知道
You do not want to knowI don't.
这是我俩之间的笑话 因为有一次
It's an inside joke, because one time,
我把一本食谱放在他的老二上
I put a cookbook on his junk right over there.
-是一本很大的食谱呢 -行了
Significant size cookbook. Okayl
我说了我不想知道 你第一次就说对了的
I said I didn't want to know. You were right the first time.
好吧 跟我一起分析一下 就一会儿
Okay. Dissect this with me, just for a second.
你觉得这是什么意思
What do you think this means?
是单纯的祝生日快乐
Is it just sort of like a simple happy birthday,
没别的意思 还是有点意思
just nothing? Like, just a little cheeky?
还是说他就是那样想念我
Or does he mean it like he's thinking about me like that?
我又开始了 我又开始了 我怎么又开始了
I'm doing it. I'm doing it. Why am I doing that?
我为什么要想什么性感暗号
Why am I trying to do the sexy secret code?
我不想这么做 对吧 我们讨论过这事儿
I don't want to do that, right? We talked about this.
我和他分手了 我要向前看了
I broke up with him. I am moving on.
目视前方的目标 我不 我不回头看
Eyes on the prize. Mnh- mnh. I don't- - I don't look back.
没错 好吧
Exactly. Okay?
好了 放一边吧
Come on. Put it away.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢了谢了
Thank you, thank you.
-手机放一边 -好
Put it awayl Okay.
我就是
I just
我知道 好吧
I know. Okay.
贝利死后我只见过丽贝卡一次
I've only seen Rebecca once since Bailey died.
想到她跟我在同一栋楼我就心塞
It is killing me to know she's in the same building.
抱歉
Ooh, sorry.
Ooh, sorry
我一直以为等我们到了这把年纪
You know, I always thought by the time we got to be this age,
所有糟心事都会烟消云散了
all the bullshit would just go away.
这就是骗人的 我的朋友
That is a lie, my friend. Yeah.
一年比一年难过
It gets harder every year.
你所有的朋友都开始结对
All your friends start pairing off
就像有洪水来袭一样
like there's some kind of flood coming.
有一天 你环顾四周 然后想着 靠 我是错过了吗
One day, you look around, and you think, shit, did I miss it?
行了 我可不信你这套
Oh come on. I don't buy that
你 你很棒 性感 而且还
You're You're awesome. You're hot, you're-
你想说的不是性感 而是极度糟糕吧
A hot mess is the term that you are searching for.
好吧 这么跟你说吧
Okay. Yeah. And guess what?
等你遇到自己的真命天子或者天女
When you do meet Miss or Mr. Right,
虽然同样是工作 但就会觉得这一切还是值得的
it's still work, but it's worth it.
威尔今晚又出警了
Will get called in tonight?
是啊 就跟我们一样
Yeah. Just like us,
总是有新案子
there's always another case.
你有艾半丽的消息吗 我以为她今晚也会来呢
You heard from Emily? I thought she was going to be here.
她就埋头于工作
She is just burying herself in work.
贝利的死对她打击挺大的
Bailey's death really hit her hard.
我是说 很明显 发生的事并不是她的错 但是
I mean, obviously, none of what happened was her fault, but- -
希望我们能说服她接受这一点
Wish we could convince her of that.
谢谢你们来参加我的趴体
Thank you for coming to my party.
你们谁要带点什么回家不
Can I offer anybody anything to take home or...?
书我肯定是不拿的
Definitely not a book. Oh.
那家伙为什么要挖出格温的眼睛
So why'd this guy gouge Gwen's eyes?
凶手是为了惩罚幸存者
The killer is punishing the survivor.
可怜的家伙
Klein: Poor bastard.
发生过多少次
How many times has this happened?
太多次了
Too many.
录音结束
Device: Recording ended.
我叫艾米丽 我是来帮你的
My name is Emily. I m here to help.
你能告诉我发生了什么吗
Can you tell me what happened?
我能看看你的手吗 可以吗
May I see your hands? Would that be okay?
没有自卫痕迹
No self- defense.
谢谢你 唐
Thank you, Don.
他需要睡会
He is going to need some sleep.
保持监视防止自杀 我明天再来
Keep him on suicide watch. I'll come back tomorrow.
抱歉这么晚叫你过来
Sorry it's so late.
。 发生什么了
What's going on?
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
好吧 我就直说了
Okay, let me get this straight.
-金星是个人 -对
Gold Star is a person? Yes.
一个嫌犯
An UnSub?
根据我目前找到的三个案子
Based on the three cases I've found so far,
一个经验丰富的嫌犯
a seasoned one.
天
Jesus.
他是躲避追捕的专家
He's an expert at evading capture.
他在不同的辖区杀人
He kills in different jurisdictions
所以很难联系起来 他只留下了识别标记
so they're hard to connect. And he's leaving a calling card.
沃伊特为什么要用那个情报对付贝利
Why would Voit use that intel against Bailey?
还有 贝利为什么要对我们隐瞒这些呢
And why would Bailey keep any of this a secret from us?
我是说 抓这种不就是我们工作的核心吗
I mean, catching guys like this is our bread and butter.
之前我在国际恐怖主义
In another life, I worked a joint task force
联合特遣部队工作
on international terrorism.
金星留下的这些子弹
Something about Gold Star leaving these bullets behind
让我想起了军队的士兵
reminds me of those playing cards
在恐怖分子尸体上留下的扑克牌
troops would leave on dead terrorists
上面写着 这是我们干的
declaring, "We did this. "
所以你认为他受过政府训练
So you think he's government trained?
他的手法过于熟练 不可能是自学的
Oh, he's too proficient to be self- taught.
那就能解释贝利为什么要保密了
Well, that would explain why Bailey kept it a secret.
我是说 那应该涉及到国家安全
I mean, that would be national security.
因为金星不再听命于人了
Because Gold Star isn't taking orders anymore.
你有可用的侧写吗
You have a working profile?
我以为我有 但今晚之后都已经无法确定了
I thought I did, but after tonight, a- all bets are off.
他已经偏离了轨道
He's strayed.
他杀死了一个假定目标的爱人
He killed the loved one of a presumed target.
他一直以任务为导向 有条理
He had been mission- oriented and methodical,
但现在似乎是某种情绪反应
but now it seems like some emotional response
在驱使他
is driving him.
好吧 听我说 因为发生在贝利身上的事
Alright. Listen. Given what happened to Bailey,
我知道你一直试图保护我们所有人
I know you've been trying to protect the rest of the team,
但如果金星一个活跃的嫌犯
but if Gold Star is an active UnSub
抱歉吵醒你 加西亚
Sorry to wake you up, Garcia.
嗨嗨嗨 你在这呢 你没事吧
Hi, hi, hi. There you are. Are you okay?
没事 谢了
Yeah. Thanks.
抱歉我没能参加你的生日趴
And I'm sorry I missed your birthday.
我会补偿你的 但首先我需要你的帮助
I'll make it up to you, but first, I need your help.
我来了
J Here we go
帮助马上就到
J Help is on the way
-说吧 -弗吉尼亚州的
Go. A police officer
名警官抱着自己妻子的尸仲
walked into his precinct in Bristow, Virginia,
走进自己辖区的布里斯托警察局 我需要他的人事档案
carrying his wife's dead body. I need personnel files,
以及所有他负责过的相关案件
any relevant cases he was working.
-他成为目标肯定是有原因的 -目标
He was targeted for a reason. Targeted?
-所以不是他干的 -不是
So he didn't do it? No.
他叫唐·贝托利
The name is Don Bertoli.
好吧 案了被标记了
Oh, okay. That case has been flagged.
份联邦档案的申请
It looks like a request for a federal file
一小时前彼批准
Credit l was approved an hour ago.
-什么 -司法部的人
Credit L What? It came from the DOJ.
丽贝卡·威尔逊申请的
Rebecca Wilson requested it.
等等 丽贝卡
Wait. Rebecca?
对
Yeah, and
好吧 这说不通啊
Okay, this doesn't make any sense.
看起来她得到了许可
It looks like she got approval to forward that file
把文件转发到一个由弗吉尼亚州
to an e- mail account that is managed
斯通沃德监狱管理的电邮账户
by a federal prison in Virginia, Stoneward Penitentiary.
丽贝卡要咨询
Who the hell's Rebecca consulting
弗吉尼亚监狱里的什么人呢
in a Virginia supermax?
好 通过
Man: Good. Clear.
很少接到艾米丽的紧急电话
Rare to get a 911 call from Emily.
是啊 昨晚开完趴这就来上班有点早了
Yeah, a little too early after the night we had.
嗯 我们有人压根就没睡
Yeah, some of us didn t sleep.
希望是本好书
Good book, I hope.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
我们刚发现伊莱亚斯·沃伊特
We just found out that Elias Voit was transferred
两周前从西雅图被转狱到维吉尼亚了
two weeks ago from Seattle to Virginia.
在那之前 他在九楼
Before that, he spent some time
-待过一段时间 -我们这栋楼吗
on the ninth floor. Of this building?
他在这待过
He was here?
谁批的转狱申请
Who the hell approved that transfer?
不管是谁 一定不想让人知道 因为我昨晚以正义之名
Whoever it was wanted to hide it, cause I traded
拿睡眠换了洞穴探险
sleep for spelunking in the name of justice.
这东西比沃伊特的集装箱埋的还深
This thing was buried deeper than Voit's containers.
这段视频是两周前录的
This footage was logged two weeks ago.
局长 没想到是你啊
Director. Wasn't expecting you.
我想见见六眼杀蛛
I wanted to meet Sicarius.
你来的有点晚了 本杰明·里弗斯已经交代了一切然后
You're a little late. Benjamin Reeves confessed and then- -
行为分析小组可不是这么想的
That's not what the BAU thinks.
行吧 行为分析小组就是无法接受我翻了个错
Yeah, well, the BAU can't accept that I made a mistake.
犯了个错
A mistake?
我为一个美国参议员的变态儿子
I created a communications network
创建了一个通讯网络
for the psychopath son of a United States senator.
我完全不知道他会利用它
I had no idea he was going to use it to chat
和全国各地的连环杀手聊天
with wannabe serial killers across the country.
等我发现他要做什么时
When I found out what he had gotten into,
他就威胁我和我的家人
he threatened me and my family.
里弗斯有很多追随者
Reeves had a lot of followers,
只要我开口 任何一个都会来追杀我
any one of whom would come after me if I opened my mouth,
所以我没说
so...I didn't.
真是
Wow. That's
你这囗才可真不错 伊莱亚斯
That's really good, Elias,
这话从你嘴里说出来就好像你自己都信了
the way it just rolled out of your mouth like you believe it.
我站在法庭上就会这么说
Imagine me on the stand.
那当我最好的助理检察官问你
Mm- hmm. And when my best AUSA asks
为什么一枪爆了道格拉斯·贝利副局长的头时
why you shot Deputy Director Douglas Bailey in the head,
你打算怎么回答
what are you going to say to that?
因为他不在你的红迪网主页上
Cause he wasn't on your little Reddit page.
我是为了自保啊
I was standing my ground.
联调局的二把手登门拜访 让我闭嘴
The FBI's second in command paid me a house call to shut me up.
我想 靠 这可大事不妙
I thought, shit, this isn't good.
于是我为了保护家人 朝道格·贝利开了枪
So I protected my family, and I shot Doug Bailey.
但你大老远把我飞到这来不是为了这事吧
But you didn't fly me across the country to talk about that.
不 你是为了弄清楚
No, you flew me across the country to talk about
为什么贝利会去我家
why Bailey was paying me that house call.
你以为自己知道什么
What do you think you know?
我知道不久之前 你回应了蝙蝠信号
I know that not long ago, you answered the bat signal.
没有眼睛的凶案受害者
Homicide victim with no eyes.
他叫杰拉尔德·富尔顿 我不知道这个名字
His name was Gerald Fulton. I don't know if that name does
对你有没有意义
or does not mean something to you,
但凶手的识别标记传达了一个信息
but what did mean something to you
这对你肯定是有意义的
was that the killer's calling card was a message.
于是开始秘密调查
And so began the secret investigation
政府代号为金星的人
into who the government codenamed Gold Star.
案件级别为非需要不许访问 你知道 贝利知道
Case was need to know. You knew. Bailey knew.
你没想到的是 我也知道
And what you weren't expecting is that I knew, too.
这就有意思了
And this is where it gets interesting,
因为你把我从西雅图转狱到这
because that's when you transfer me from Seattle
是为了帮你阻止
out here to help you
相关信息的传播
stop the spread of a contagion.
你跟金星交谈过
You talked to Gold Star?
也许
Maybe.
你的通讯网络将数百人联系到一起
Your communication network connected hundreds of people.
所以你跟他联系过
You talked to him?
也许
Maybe.
光说也许可不行
I'm going to need more than a maybe.
我需要你给出确切的是或者不是
I'm going to need a yes or no.
我需要台电脑
Well, I need a computer.
别特么跟我扯淡了
Get the fuck out of here.
电脑落到你手里比一把上了膛的枪还危险
A computer in your hands is more dangerous than a loaded gun.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
告诉我他的位置
Give me his location.
好吧 你不能给我电脑
Okay, you can't give me a computer.
但我可以给你的
But what I can give you,
局长
Director,
是为什么金星会杀人
is why Gold Star kills.
这可是连行为分析小组都给不了你的
And not even the BAU can give you that.
说来听听
Enlighten me.
白听吗
For free?
我不是在跟你谈判
This is not a negotiation.
行吧 你就这么跟自己说吧
Okay, just keep telling yourself that.
给我点有用的东西 我可以考虑一下
Give me something I can use. Maybe I'll think about it.
算了
Pass
我们都知道金星还会再次杀人
We both know Gold Star is going to kill again.
等他那么做时 我可能就会抬价了
And when he does, my price is going to go up
越抬越高
and up and up.
大卫·罗西
David Rossi,
联调局的传奇 也是我崇拜的人
an FBI legend and someone I- I looked up to,
可他却跟踪我和我的家人
he was stalking me and my family.
我老婆 西德尼 她是
My wife, Sydney, she's the
是我见过的最坚强的女人
the strongest woman I've ever known,
但是当 当他在那个市场里看到了她 她
but when when he found her in that market, she- -
是 助理检察官女土
And yes, Miss AUSA,
把他埋到地堡里是我反应过激了
burying him in a bunker was an overreaction,
但是我 我受到了极度的胁迫
but I I was under extreme duress.
让我上庭啊 只要有一个陪审员信就够了
Go ahead and put me on trial. It only takes one juror.
如果你给联调局提供了有用的信息
If you provide the Bureau with actionable information
让我们逮捕并给金星定罪
that leads to the apprehension and conviction of Gold Star,
司法部愿意和你做笔交易
the DOJ is prepared to offer you a deal.
你可以对绑架联邦探员的罪名认罪
You could plead guilty to the abduction of a federal agent,
最高可判15年监禁
which carries a maximum prison sentence of 15 years.
丐年后可以假释
Eligible for parole in five.
这提议不错
It's a nice offer.
但不够完整
But it's incomplete.
行为分析小组立案调查我
The BAU, they're building a case
好像我是他们见过的最坏的连环杀手
that I'm the worst serial killer they've ever seen.
条件就是这样
The offer's the offer.
那就谈不成咯
Well, then there's no deal.
也就是说
Which means you are going to waste
你要浪费大量纳税人的钱
a whole lot of taxpayer money
来证明他们的观点
trying to prove their side when there is
没有DNA 什么都没有
no DNA Nothing.
本杰明·里弗斯认罪后 连总检察长都亲自结案了
The A. G. herself closed the case when Benjamin Reeves confessed.
你答应我永远不会被指控为六眼杀蛛
You're going to agree that I'm never charged as Sicarius,
我就会告诉你我知道的一切
and I'll tell you everything I know.
就这么多
Garcia: And that's it.
他能这么做吗
He can do that?
答应跟一个连环杀手合作
Just agree to work with a prolific killer?
我们没法证明他是六眼杀蛛
We can't prove he's Sicarius.
我们知道沃伊特会有后备计划 这就是
We knew Voit would have a backup plan. This was it.
金星到底是什么东西
What the hell is Gold Star?
当你在实地部署的时候
When you were boots on the ground,
沃伊特嘲笑贝利
Voit was taunting Bailey
说他总是能得到一颗金星
about always getting a gold star.
他说话的口吻 好像对贝利来说很有意义
The way he said it, it meant something to Bailey.
所以他才坚持要和你们一起去加州
It's why he insisted on joining you all in California.
那他为什么没等我们自己进去了
And why he went inside without us.
沃伊特把贝利引诱到加州之后
Once Voit lured Bailey out to California,
他的怀疑被证实了
his suspicions were confirmed,
然后金星就成了他谈判的筹码
and then Gold Star became his bargaining chip.
所以 这到底是什么
So...what is it?
我的理论是 金星是个
My theory is Gold Star is a killer
政府受训的杀手
trained by the government.
可能是骑警 可能是海豹突击队 也有可能是中情局
Could be Rangers, could be Seal Team, could be the Agency.
但哪一方都没承认过
None will ever admit it.
杀手就是机器 他们的工作就是杀人
Assassins are machines. It's their job to kill
他为什么会成为杀手 这才是我门需要侧写的
Why did he become an assassin? That's what we need to profile.
对 还有 为什么局长不寻求帮助呢
Yeah, and also, why didn't the Director ask us for help?
多不可能的侧写我们以前都做过
We've profiled the super impossible before.
他不想让我们插手
He didn't want our eyes on it.
你觉得他在隐瞒什么吗
You think he's hiding something?
-不是吧 会是什么呢 -我不知道
Really? Like what? I don't know.
但是很明显 他不顾一切的想要达成交易
But he was desperate enough to try to make the deal.
但他到最后应该没答应吧
But he didn't follow through, did he?
他答应了 六眼杀蛛的指控被撤销了
Yes, he did. The Sicarius charges are off the table.
怎么会这样
How is this happening?
总检察长和局长肯定认为
The A. G. and Director must think Gold Star
金星事关国家安全
is a national security issue.
草
Rossi: Fuck!
要我去看看他吗
You want me to check on him?
给他点时间吧
Give him a minute.
我马上回来
Lewis: I'll be right back.
收到你的消息了 什么事
Rebecca: I got your text. What's up?
不是吧
Really?
塔拉 我忙的不可开交
Tara, I'm pulled in a million directions.
这次我又怎么让你失望了
How have I disappointed you this time?
局长和沃伊特做的交易
The deal the Director made with Voit.
你也参与了吗
Did you have any part in that?
是你给沃伊特去送的档案吗
Are you the one debriefing Voit?
怎么着 局长达成了交易后
Because what, the Director, he made the deal, but he
就不想再沾手了 是吧
wouldn't want to get his hands any dirtier, now, would he?
我奉命不得谈论此事
I'm under orders not to discuss any of this.
行了你 够了 是我啊
Oh, stop that. Stop it This is me.
你真的信沃伊特胜过行为分析小组吗
You really have more faith in Voit than the BAU?
-我只是在做好本职工作 -那就连
I'm just doing my job. Yeah, well, at the expense
常识都不要了吗 你真的觉得可以信任一个
of common sense? Do you really think you can trust
变态连环杀手而不是信任我们吗
a psychopathic serial killer more than you can trust us?
至少他没对我撒谎
Well, at least he didn't lie to me.
天
Jesus.
这就是 我就该
This is just I should have
你就该怎样
You should have whart?
我早该知道一对在匿名互助会认识的伴侣
I should have known that a couple who met at Al Anon
会有边界问题
would have boundary issues.
所以你才乐于
Oh, oh that's why you're willingj
让伊莱亚斯·沃伊特离开监狱吗 边界
to let Elias Voit out of prison? Boundaries?
不 所以你不能接受
No, it's why you can't accept
我的职责包括处理敏感信息
that I have a duty that includes handling sensitive information.
边界
Boun- da- ries.
我没想那么结束我们之间的关系 这是真心话
You know, I hate how we ended. I really dlo.
但我想我们还可以做朋友
But I thought we could be friends.
我也是 只不过我不会为了要做自己的事
Me, too. Except I don't ask my friends
而让我的朋友拿他们的工作冒险
to risk their job so I can do mine.
你写到 出其不意的因素被低估了
Voit: You wrote, The element of surprise is underrated.
没有意外的生活就不是生活
Life would not be life without curveballs. "
-你这样不会有好果子的 -怎样
You won't get away with it With what?
用秘密换取自由
Trading secrets for your freedom.
肯定没法保证 大卫
It's not a guarantee, Dave.
除非我的情报能把他抓起来
It's only if my intel gets him apprehended.
所以我们俩要开始竞赛了
So you and I are in a race.
先抓到金星的就能赢
Whoever gets to Gold Star first wins.
你本该早点告诉我的
You could have told me sooner.
我也是刚看到视频
I just saw that footage myself.
好吧 但是自从贝利的葬礼之后
Okay, but you've been looking into Gold Star
你就在调查金星
since Bailey's funeral.
我认为金星害死了贝利
I think Gold Star got Bailey killed.
但除非我了解到更多 否则就不能冒险拖你下水
And I couldn't risk involving you until I knew more.
别这样 贝利的死又不是你的错
Come on. Bailey's death isn on you.
我知道
I know.
那你最后一次睡觉是什么时候
And when was the last time you slept?
你最后一次去接受心理治疗是什么时候
When's the last time you went to mandated trauma therapy?
扃 行吧
Alright.
我们会支持彼此 一向如此
We have each other's back. Always have.
但你之前告诉我这负担不是我一个人的
But you told me a while ago this burden isn't mine alone.
这话我也送给你
Well, back at you.
我们必须赶在沃伊特之前找到金星
We have to find Gold Star before Voit does.
没错 否则不管局长交易的背后
Yes, we do, or whatever it is
用意是什么 都是扯淡
that's behind the Director's deal is bullshit.
贝利死后 我开始查所有
Prentiss: When Bailey died, I started looking
跟金星有关的信息
for anything involving a gold star,
然后我在安纳波利斯发现了一些信息
and I found something in Annapolis.
杰拉尔德·富尔顿 38岁^纳尔泰克安全焦团的分析师
Gerald Fulton, 38, an analyst for the Naltek Security Group.
尽管看起来像是一次性行为
Although it appeared to be a one- off,
但这种暴力事件也值得我们调查
the violence was worthy of our consult.
但我们没接到电话 局长接到了
But we didn't get the call. The Director did.
金星似乎有一种冲动
Gold Star seems to have a compulsion
要留下自己的识别标记
to leave behind a calling card.
是一个刻在弹壳上的五角星
It's a five- point star etched into a bullet casing.
这表明他的动机是什么
What's that say about his motivation?
为什么要剜目
And why enucleate?
我也这么想的
Well, I wondered the same thing.
于是我在华盛顿方圆100英里的范围内搜索了一下
So I did a search within a 100- mile radius of D. C,
然后我找到了阿图罗·门德斯 27岁 机械工程师
and that's when I found Arturo Mendez, 27, mechanical engineer.
在门德斯的枪里发现了弹壳
Bullet casing was found in Mendez's gun.
这让我很好奇 为什么一个机械工程师
And that got me wondering, why would a mechanical engineer
要带枪去上班呢
even bother carrying a gun to work?
然后我又发现了肖恩·里格斯 35岁 保险推销员
Then I found Sean Riggs, 35, insurance salesman,
枪里有金星的子弹
Gold Star casing in his gun.
这些场景 在这种不受控制的环境中杀戮
These scenes, they're efficient and bold,
虽然有点戏剧性 但却是有效而大胆的
albeit dramatic, to kill in such uncontrolled environments.
这么公开的 如此冒险
It's very risky, very public.
他还把尸体摆出有震撼效果的姿势
He poses the bodies for shock value.
也许他觉得自己是个信使
Maybe he sees himself as a messenger
想让大家感到恐惧
wants to instill fear
在空旷的地方袭击表现了他的自信
Well, attacking in the open shows confidence.
沃伊特很自负 但他在黑暗中杀害并埋葬受害者
Voit's arrogant, but he killed and buried his victims
隐藏了他的秘密
in the dark, hid his secrets.
沃伊特充满羞愧
Voit was full of shame.
他不想让家人知道他做了什么
He never wanted his family to know what he'd done.
这家伙毫无悔意 毫无遗憾
Yeah, this guy has no remorse, no regret
好吧 所以也许金星就是沃伊特的反面
Lewis: Okay, so maybe Gold Star is the exact opposite of Voit
没有家人 没有关系 没人能追究他的责任
No family, no ties, no one to hold him accountable.
也没有人能阻止他一次又一次杀人
No one to stop him from killing again and again.
最初的犯罪现场有保安
The initial crime scene locations had security,
但他干扰了监控
but he scrambled the feed.
金星受过专业训练 考虑到了一切
Prentiss: Gold Star has been trained to think of everything.
我们需要深入他的思想中去
We need to get inside his mind.
为什么选择这些受害人 为什么选择现在
starting with why these victims, why now?
三个人 三个辖区
Three men, three jurisdictions,
三个不同的职业
three different occupations.
但所有的受害人都带枪
But all of the victims carried guns.
好吧 如果这些信息还不够 还有个意外状况
Okay, if that wasn't enough, here's the curveball.
昨晚的受害人 格温·贝托利41岁
Last night's victim, Gwen Bertoli, 41.
她在各方面都是与其他受害人不同
She was a departure in every way,
首先她是在自己家里被杀的
first to be killed in her own home.
格温是个美甲师
Garcia: Gwen was a nail technician.
嫁给了警官唐·贝托利
She was married to police officer Don Bertoli.
猜猜在他的警用枪里发现了什么
Guess what was found in his police issued firearm?
格温也是第一个被金星杀的女人
Gwen's also the first woman Gold Star's killed.
是 但这并不是为了杀死她
Yeah, but this isn't just about killing her.
我是说 很明显这是为了惩罚她丈夫
I mean, it's clearly about punishing the husband.
精神上的痛苦优先
Mental suffering took priority.
不管是什么 都被埋葬了
Prentiss: Well, whatever it is, it's buried.
贝托利精神受创 但他是我们唯一的机会
Bertoli's catatonic, but he's our only shot.
大卫 我们俩去跟他谈谈
Dave, you and I are going to go talk to him.
卢克 深挖一下格温·贝托利的犯罪现场照片
JJ, Luke, dig into Gwen Bertoli's crime scene photos.
佩内洛普 塔拉 你们能去查出
Penelope, Tara, can you find out everything
局长让丽贝卡告诉沃伊特的一切吗
the Director told Rebecca to share with Voigt?
我虽然不想承认 但他的确是领先我们了
I hate to admit it, but he's way ahead of us.
这个王八蛋肯定跟这个人联络过
That son of a bitch talked to this guy,
对不对 在他的网络里
didn't he? On his network.
即便是真的 他也从没承认过
Prentiss: Even if he did, he'd never admit it.
如果我们不能先找到金星
If we don't find Gold Star first,
沃伊特就能逃脱一切责任
Voit gets away with everything.
这个金星没有破窗
Well, this Gold Star didn't break any windows
也并非强行进入
or force his way in.
如果贝托利夫妇认识他呢
What if the Bertolis knew him?
这就解释了没有强行进入的痕迹
It explains the lack of forced entry.
没有挣扎迹象
There were no signs of a struggle
贝托利块头很大 他为什么不还手
I mean, Bertoli's a big guy. Why didn't he fight back?
如果有人拿枪指着我家入 我也会听话的
Well, if someone pulls a gun on my family, I'd comply.
他还把他们绑起来过
He also zip- tied them,
但后来又给松开了
but cut them loose.
他不怕他们会跑为什么要让他们坐下来呢
He wasn't afraid they'd run. Why sit them down at all?
在那待那么久太戏剧化了 还很冒险
I mean, it's dramatic and risky to spend so much time there.
他让他们面对面坐下
He had them face one another.
他让唐无力还手 逼他看着
He rendered Don powerless and forced him to watch.
真是残酷至极的惩罚
That's a really brutal punishment.
为什么呢
Why?
我 真的好气哦
Garcia: Ugh, I am j I am so ticked
沃伊特比我们先知道这个什么受训政府的金星
that Voit knew about this Gold Star gobbledygook before we did.
我们之前知道他在策划些事
Lewis: Well, we figured he had something in the works.
现在知道是什么事了 那他的追随者呢
Now we know what. And what about his acolytes?
要么沉寂 要么灭绝
Well, either dormant or extinct.
他说服所有拥有杀人工具包的人自杀
And he convinced all the guys with kill kits
他控制影响力太大了
to off themselves. He had so much control.
他就是吃这口饭的 看看他现在
He lives for this shit. I mean, look at him now.
即便被关起来 还是能找到法子控制别人
He's locked up, and he still found a way to get control.
不管他认不认识金星
Whether he knows Gold Star or not,
他都说服了局长他有巨大价值
he convinced the Director that he's of immense value,
这才是最重要的
and that's all that matters.
天 要完成这一切
God, to pull this off,
你必须非常小心谨慎
you'd have to be incredibly meticulous.
完美无缺的作案手法 仪式
Perfect the M. O. and the ritual,
选择特定的受害者类型
select a specific victim type.
但昨晚 他打破了自己的模式
But then last night, he breaks from his pattern.
我是说 为什么杀了个女人
I mean, why kill a woman,
还留了个活口 这也太变态了
then Ieave a survivor? It's sadistic.
是啊 就跟其他的不变态一样
Yeah, like the other ones weren't.
是变态 但他让其他男人从痛苦中解脱了
Sure, but he put those other men out of their misery.
他想让贝托利继续遭罪
He wanted Bertoli to keep suffering.
也许他知道什么 因为我们这里有三个死去的男性
Maybe he knew something. Cause we've got three dead dudes
以及一个女性 这个女人嫁给了一个可能身怀
and a woman married to a guy who might have had a secret
惊天大秘密 大到会害她丧命的男人
that's so gigantically huge, it got her killed.
那么秘密是什么呢
So what is that secret?
都在这里了
Well, it's all here.
我们只需要继续挖
We just have to keep digging.
贝托利妻子在他面前被杀
Bertoli's wife is murdered in front of him,
但他没报警 而是走了三英里
but he doesn't call 911. Instead, he walks three miles.
他吓坏了 还没说过话
Well, he's in shock. He hasn't even talked yet.
几乎没合过眼 可能没法开车
Barely blinks. Probably couldn't drive,
于是他走到了个安全的地方
and so he walked to a safe place.
一路上都拖着个尸体
Carrying dead weight all that way?
可能是训练或习得的行为
Could be training or learned behavior.
所以你认为是事情出岔子了
So you're thinking shit gets sideways,
他得回到大本营
he's got to get back to base camp.
贝托利服过役吗
Did Bertoli serve?
他档案里没有 但带着他死去妻子的尸体
It's not in his file, but a three- mile walk
走了三英里都没被人看到吗
carrying his dead wife's body, and no one saw him?
我是艾米丽·普兰蒂斯 我们昨晚见过
It's Emily Prentiss. We met last night.
这是我同事 大卫·罗西 我们是联调局的
This is my colleague, David Rossi. We're with the FBI.
唐 唐 做点什么啊 求你了
Gwen: Don? Don? Do something, please,
唐 节哀顺变
Don, we're all very sorry for your loss.
去拿枪 他会杀了我们的
Gwen: Get your gun. He's gonna kill us.
你知道是谁干的吗
But do you have any idea who might have done this?
唐
Gwen: Don!
怎么了
Rossi: What is it?
别让他这么做啊 唐
Don't let him do this, Don!
冷静 没事的 唐
Rossi: Easy. It's alright, Don.
是这样 就 回来坐好
Look, just- just get back in your seat.
-唐 -快点 坐下
Prentiss: Don? Officer Come on, sit down.
我天 求求你住手
Gwen: Oh, my God! Please stop!
来 坐下
Come on, get back.
唐
Prentiss: Don!
唐 住手
Rossi: Don, stop.
我们需要增援
We need backupl
唐
Prentiss: Don!
唐 住手
Don, stop.
唐 唐 把枪放下
Don, Don. Put the pistol down.
放下
Just put it down.
唐 不要啊 不要 放下 别 别开枪
Don? No! No! Put it down! Don't, don't, don't!
不
Prentiss: No!
贝托利说什么了吗
Did Bertoli say anything?
一个字都没说
Not a word.
他不仅是个悲痛的丈夫
He's more than a grieving husband.
有件事我没想明白 他就没报过警
Something s bugging me. He never called 911
而是背着他死去的妻子走了三英里
Instead, he walked three miles carrying his dead wife.
怎么就没人发现他呢
Somehow he wasn't spotted?
我觉得他知道要避开主干道
I'm thinking he knew to stay off the main roads,
避免被发现 就像在执行任务一样
avoid detection, like he was on a mission.
他绝对接受过高等训练
Well, he s definitely highly trained
如果更具体的说是心理战训练呢
What if it's more specifically psy- ops training?
你怎么想到这点的
How did you get there?
创伤诱发的分离症状
Trauma- induced dissociation
可能表现为那样的本然状态
can present in a catatonic state like that,
就像他进入了为了自我保护的恍惚状态
but it's like he went into a trance, but to protect himself.
我不相信我会这么说
Look, I can't believe I'm going to say this,
但这正是格林擅长的
but this is right in Green's wheelhouse.
-格林 -对
Green? Yeah.
泰勒·格林的那个格林
As in Tyler Green?
我们不能问他
We can't ask him.
他妨碍过一次调查
He compromised an investigation.
局长在和沃伊特达成协议的时候 撕毁了那份文件
Which the Director tore up when he made Voit's deal.
如果泰勒有什么见解 我认为我们应该听听
If Tyler has any insight, I say we take it.
大卫 有什么异议吗
Dave, any objections?
佩内洛普
Penelope?
我从没想过还能再见到你们
I never thought that I'd see any of you again.
对于发生的一切 我很抱歉
I'm sorry for everything.
我当时太专注于抓沃伊特了
I was so focused on catching Voit-
我曾经也像你一样
I was just like you once.
我以为自己可以独自完成一切
I thought I could do it all by myself.
但不能 不过有意思的是
But you can't The funny thing, though-
你的独自行动却救了我
g You going rogue saved me.
-真的吗 -你那种出现方式
Really? Well, showing up like you did
既愚蠢又鲁莽 别再那样了
was stupid and reckless. Don't do that
但也是意外之举 沃伊特不得不调整计划
But it was also a curvevball. Voit had to adjust.
因为他调整了 我才还在这儿
And because he did, I'm still here.
所以谢谢
So thank you.
接受你的道歉 现在
And apology accepted. Now
我们需要你的帮助
we need your help.
唐 我是艾米丽·普伦蒂斯
Don? It's Emily Prentiss.
我们昨晚见过 这是我同事
We met last night. This is my colleague.
我们认为他处于创伤诱发的分离状态
We thought he was in a trauma- induced dissociative state.
-他这样多久了 -在此之前超过12小时
How long was he like that? Over 12 hours before this.
他接受过近身格斗技巧训练
He's been trained in close quarter combat techniques.
我们也这么想 但没参军记录
We were thinking the same, but there's no military record.
他不需要服役
He didn't need to serve.
我们也找不到贝托利和
We also can't find any connection between Bertoli
之前受害者的联系
and the earlier victims.
你能看一下吗
Would you take a look?
也许能告诉我们有没有遗漏的地方
Maybe tell us if we're missing something.
我们知道你有 |比
We know you have contacts
可能有价值的人脉
that could prove...valuable.
也许有
I might.
如果你已经断了联系 说一声就好
If you've cut ties, just say the word.
我先看看
Let me take a look.
也许不需要找援军
Might not need to call reinforcements.
-谢谢 泰勒 -我的荣幸
Thank you, Tyler. My pleasure.
他们居然真让他来当顾问
They are actually going to have him consult.
你当时怎么就没闭嘴呢
Why didn't you keep your trap shut?
我们最大的线索刚刚自杀了
Our biggest lead just killed himself.
如果行为分析组和沃伊特在比赛找金星
If it's BAU versus Voit in the race to find Gold Star
沃伊特可是遥遥领先
Voit is way ahead of us.
-我们需要秘密武器 -是
We need a secret weapon. Yeah.
他看起来很累 不知道他有没有睡
He looks tired. Wonder if he's sleeping.
我看起来不错吧 我棒极了
I look good, right? I'm great
我做了自我肯定的暗示
I've made affirmations.
这里有些例子 永远的宝贝女
Here are some. Baby girl forever.
我的猫就是我男友 特别就是优秀
My cats are my boyfriend. Special is great
-嘿 别叨叨了 -怎么了 我得
Hey, stop. What? I need to...
嘿 泰勒
Hey, Tylerl
我刚还在想你呢
Wow. You know, I was just thinking about you.
我刚在想那次
I was just thinking about that time
你当我们所有人面撒谎
that you lied to all of our faces,
自作主张
and you took the law into your own hands.
还记得吗 真是
Do you remember that? That was
真是疯狂 对你有什么影响吗
That was crazy! How'd that work out for you?
我知道了 明白你意思了
I got it. Message received.
但是 你们看哈 我会在这里待一阵子 当顾问
But, look, I'm gonna be around a bit, consulting.
那我就先跳进这个尴尬的局面
So I'm just going to dive head first into the awkwardness
表达一下再见到你们很高兴吧
and say I'm happy to see you again.
你们 不是那么高兴
You, not so much.
什么 我吗 那你可是没赶上
What, me? Oh, you are missing out.
好吧 我要做什么
Okay, what do I need?
我放下过去为未来腾出空间
Uh, I let go of my past to make room for my future.
我们继续 他近距离看起来好很多
Uh, onward we go. He looked better up close.
我之前还有点担心呢 但我不介意
I was worried, but stillI'm good.
我跟他是分手了 但还是可以在同一个空间里共存的
I broke up with him. We can exist in the same space.
我好极了 嘿 卢克
I am great. Oh, hey, Luke?
谢谢你啊
Thank you for that.
不客气
You're welcome.
好 注意安全
Okay. Be safe.
猫就是我的男友
Cats are my boyfriends.
局长希望你能给我们点什么
The Director is expecting you to give us something.
眼睛很戏剧化
Voit: The eyes are dramatic,
但需要被接收才能有效
but it needs to be received in order to be effective,
所以这个叫贝托利的
hence this Bertoli guy.
几小时前自杀了
Took his life a few hours ago.
我猜猜啊 用的警察的枪
Let me guess. An officer's gun?
是的
Yeah.
阿尔法型人格不喜欢失去控制
Alphas don't like to lose control.
所以金星早就知道贝托利从本然状态中
So Gold Star knew that when Bertoli was out
恢复过来时 就会自杀
of his catatonic state, he'd off himself.
但他想先折磨他
But he wanted to make him suffer first.
问题是为什么
Mm- hmm. Question is why?
行为分析小组就是为此而生的 他们喜欢用
The BAU, they live for that. They like to take
综合性的办法来解决问题
the whole child approach to figuring it out, you know,
类似于360度观察杀手的成长背景
sort of a 360- degree view of the killer's upbringing,
他们是如何被忽视 虐待的 所有这些
how they were neglected, abused, all that
所以我会帮你节省359度
So I will save you 359 degrees
直接带你去你要去的地方
and get you exactly where you need to be.
这些杀人 还有闹翻
These killings and the fallout?
都是为了复仇
All about vengeance.
复什么仇 被害人之间没有联系啊
For what? The victims aren't connected.
当然是有的
Sure they are.
金星有 份目标清单
Gold Star has a list of targets.
还有一个 然后他就会销声匿迹
There's going to be one more, then he'll go underground.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
这是沃伊特所说的他的行为模式
That's what Voit said about the pattern.
他说还会有一个类似的被害者
He said there's one more like the rest,
然后就结束了 他不肯再多说了
and then that's it. He won't tell me anything else.
还会有一个类似的被害者 他现在成尤达大师了吗
One more like the rest. Voit's Yoda now?
他有告诉你被害者之间有什么联系吗
Did he tell you how the victims are connected?
没有
No.
好吧 等等 等一下
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait a minute.
沃伊特知道这些人为什么会被盯上 但我们不知道吗
Voit knows why these people were targeted, but we don't?
如果他要得到承认
He's going to have to do way better than that
那这些肯定是不够的
if he wants credit.
金星是 是在执行某种任务吗
Is...Is Gold Star on a mission?
我不知道
I don't know.
我现在能告诉你的只有这么多了
That's all I can give you right now.
我都不该跟你说这些的
I shouldn't even be talking to you.
等等
Wait.
你为什么要这样
Why are you doing this?
可能我是讨厌自己现在所做的事情
Maybe I hate what I'm doing.
可能我是想帮你们抓住金星
Maybe I want to help you catch Gold Star
这样那狗娘养的沃伊特就能
so that that son of a bitch Voit rots in prison
下半辈子烂在监狱里了
for the rest of his life.
也可能
Or maybe
我不知道
I don't know.
可能我不懂边界感
Maybe I have boundary issues.
金星会不会是让他们彼此对峙
What if Gold Star had them face one another
因为他希望让唐·贝尔托利坦白一些事情
because he wanted Don Bertoli to confess something?
唐不敢在他老婆面前说 因为觉得太丢人了
And Don was too ashamed to say it in front of his wife.
是啊 他可能有另一套人生 或者是过去犯下的罪行 或者
Yeah, he could have had a secret life, a sin from the past or...
唐·贝尔托利遭到了最糟糕的折磨
The worst possible thing happened to Don Bertoli,
但他还是没有对你们坦白
but he still didn't come clean to either of you.
他保持了沉默 对吧
He was silent, right?
喂 你没资格就这样闯进来
Oy. You do not have barging privileges.
我们 你刚打断了JJ说话
And we- You just interrupted JJ.
抱歉 JJ
Uh, sorry, JJ.
贝托利的那种类似昏迷状态
Bertoli being all comatose- like
让我想起了执行任务之后的状态
reminded me of what it was like after a mission.
我会彻底封闭起来 当时我自己没有意识到
I'd shut down. Didn't know it then,
但是我可以肯定那是羞愧与创伤的循环
but pretty sure it's this loop of shame and trauma …
丽贝卡刚告诉我 沃伊特说
Rebecca just told me that Voit says
这些被害者之间是有联系的
these victims are connected and that there's going to be
而且再杀一个人 金星就会销声匿迹
one more before Gold Star goes underground. 旦
-这些被害者有什么联系 -沃伊特不肯说
The victims are connected how? Voit's not saying.
有道理 听着 我在这些被害人的
That tracks. Look, I found something strange
财务记录里发现了一些奇怪的东西
in all of the victims financial records.
我以前在反情报做事的时候见过
Something I've seen before in counterintelligence.
他们所有人都有外国银行挂钩的
Each one of them has a record of a third party escrow account
第三方托管账户
tied to a foreign bank
虽然没有可以追踪的金钱交易报告
There are no currency transaction reports to trace,
但这就是那种在大规模破坏行动中
but it is exactly the kind of offshore account
用来支付机械工酬金的离岸账户
that's used to pay"mechanics"in bang- and- burn operations.
给我
Give me that.
你说的是破坏和暗杀那种事情
You're talking about things like sabotage or assassination.
或者在本案中 收钱去除掉金星
Or in this case, being paid to take out Gold Star.
我觉得这些被害人都属于同一支突击小队
I think these victims were a strike team,
金星是想要复仇
and Gold Star wants revenge.
该死的 他说的对
Garcia: Damn it. He's right.
我查不到钱来自于哪里
I can't see where the money's coming from.
但是这上面有两个名字 不是一个
But there are two names, not one.
行 所以沃伊特骗了丽贝卡
Okay, so Voit's lying to Rebecca.
或者他是在设计我们
Or he's setting us up.
两个目标都是本地人
Garcia: Both targets are local.
特雷弗·卡莱尔和艾萨克·桑切斯
Uh, Trevor Carlyle and Isaac Sanchez.
他们俩之中肯定有一个能确认金星身份
One of them has to be able to identify Gold Star.
我们必须立刻对他们实施保护性监禁
We need to get them into protective custody right now.
卡莱尔住在华盛顿东南
Carlyle is in southeast D. C.
好 我去找后援 跟他们到现场汇合
Alright, I'm gonna call in backup and meet them on- site.
我跟你去
I'm with you.
-另个是警察 -把坐标发给我们
Another police officer. Send us the coordinates.
-我们走 -发了
Prentiss: Let's go. Garciai Done.
我 不好意思
I- - Excuse me.
我 我的家人
Sanchez: My My family.
听着 我 我可以帮你
Look, I I can help you.
让我帮你 我和你
Let me help you out of this. Me and you,
我们可以一起搞定这件事的
we can work through this together.
让我帮你 我们一起 我可以帮你
Let me help you. Together. Together. I can help you.
听着 你不需要这样的
Look, you don't have to do this.
我们可以解决这件事的
We can work this out.
你没必要这样的
You don't have to do this!
不 不
No. No!
不 不 不
Aah! No, no, no!
联调局 手举起来 手
Alvez: FBII Let me see your handsl Hands!
卡莱尔已经死了有一段时间了
Carlyle's been dead for a long time.
他肯定是金星的第一个被害人
Must have been Gold Star's first victim.
突袭 联调局
Man: Breaching! FBI!
客厅没人
Living room, clear.
把束缚带解开
Prentiss: Get those restraints off.
去后面看看
Man: Check the back!
立刻把他放到地上 快
Man#2: Get him on the floor quickl
是金星千的吗
Did Gold Star do this?
他是谁 我们需要一个名字
Who is he? We need a name.
桑切斯 告诉我们是谁把你变成这样的
Sanchez, tell us who did this to you.
老天 他舌头被人割了
Man: Jesus. His tongue's been cut out.
-保住他的命 -坚持住
Keep him alive. Stay with me.
保住他的命坚持住
Keep him aliveiStay with me
-他在大出血 -舌下动脉断了
Womani Hels hemorrhaging Sublingual artery's cut.
用力按压
Energy on compressions.
脉搏很微弱 他失血很多
Pulse is tachy Hels losing a lot of blood,
坚持住 桑切斯
Rossi: Hang in there, Sanchez.
拜托 坚持住
Come on. Stay with me.
他不行了
He's coding.
桑切斯是我们最后的机会了
Sanchez was our last chance.
暂时是的 但我们会想到别的办法的
For now, but we'll think of something.
你们准备告诉我这他妈的到底是怎么回事吗
You want to tell me what the hell's going on?
好问题
Great question.
恕我直言 长官
AlI due respect, sir,
你不该和伊莱亚斯·沃伊特达成协议的
you never should have made that deal with Elias Voit
他有情报能帮我们抓到
He has intel to capture someone
一个不想被发现的人
who doesn't want to be found.
他是怎么得到这情报的
And how does he have this intel?
为达目的不择手段
Look, you use every tool in the box to get the job done.
我知道你们对他有意见
I know you have an issue with him.
-他要杀我诶 -但这不是没杀死你吗
Hey, he tried to kill meBut he didn't
你都无计可施到这种程度了吗
You're going to go with that?
我来告诉你们 接下来怎么办
Let me tell you what's going to happen.
我们不会继续做目标不同的工作了
We aren't going to work at cross- purposes anymore.
挺好 你撤掉和沃伊特的协议
Alright, good. Well, you take the deal with Voit
我们就把抓到金星作为第一要务
off of the table, and we'll make Gold Star our top priority.
这样吧 我接受你一半的建议
Tell you what I'll take you up
你要猜猜是哪一半吗
on half of that suggestion. You want to guess which half?
金星的政治负担这么大吗
Gold Star is that much of a political liability?
那个男人 不管他的真名是什么
That man, whatever his real name is,
已经证明了 他是个明显的巨大威胁
has proven himself to be a clear and present danger.
所以既然你们主动提出把抓他当成第一要务
So since you volunteered to make catching him your top priority,
那行为分析小组就要和伊莱亚斯·沃伊特合作去实现它
the BAU will work with Elias Voit to make that happen.
-不行 -不行也得行
We will not. Oh, you most certainly will.
我们不会依赖于
We will not rely
一个连环杀手的帮助
on help from a serial killer
来建立侧写的
to build our profile.
那还不如让我们辞职
We will resign before that happens.
我没意见
Fine with me.
给你点专业建议 艾米丽
Pro tip, Emily. Don't threaten me
别用会让我更轻松的事情来威胁我
with the very thing that makes my life easier.
长官
Sir Uh
没事 局长 我们合作
that's fair, Director. We'll cooperate.
很聪明丽贝卡·威尔逊会担任联络人
Smart choice. Rebecca Wilson will liaise
方便联调局和司法部之间合作
just to grease the wheels between the FBI and DOJ.
-行 还有一件事 -什么事
Fine. Oh, uh, one more thing. What's that?
泰勒·格林 他有参与过
Tyler Green, he has this background
军事心理行动的经历
in military psychological operations.
在这种案子里比较有用
He could be useful in a case like this.
我们希望请他作为顾问
We'd like to add him on as a consultant.
-泰勒·格林吗 -对
Tyler Green? Mm- hmm.
不给证件 不能持枪
No badge, no gun.
没问题
No problem.
我不说祝你们好运 因为我不信这个
I don't say good luck cause I don't believe in it.
给我拿出结果来
Just get me results.
偏偏是你 和沃伊特合作
You, of all people. Work with Voit?
我有个计划
I have a plan.
我不太喜欢这个想法
I can't say I like the idea.
是 但我们没有别的线索了
Yeah, but we don't have any other leads.
他今晚都没有留下识别标记
He didn't even leave his calling card tonight.
他完成了任务 所以不需要传达讯息了
He's completed his mission. He's done sending messages.
不一定 根据警方报告
Maybe, maybe not. According to the police report,
艾萨克·桑切斯的警徽不见了
Isaac Sanchez's badge is nowhere to be found.
行 所以他今晚没有留下金星 而是带走了一个
Okay, so he didn't leave a gold star tonight. He took one.
这会改变侧写的
It's going to change our profile.
这一点 我们还他妈得去咨询伊莱亚斯·沃伊特
We have to ask fucking Elias Voit's opinion on the matter.
是 但关键就在这里
Rossi: Yes, we do. But here's the rub.
89年的时候 联调局在绿河谋杀案中
Back in 89, the FBI asked Ted Bundy
咨询了泰德·邦迪的意见
about the Green River murders.
邦迪意外说漏了一些他之前未承认过的
Bundy accidentally admitted in details about his own murders
关于他自己罪行的细节
that he hadn't admitted to before.
所以你觉得我们有机会
So you think we might be able to get Voit
让沃伊特自证其罪吗
to incriminate himself?
这对局长来说没区别
It won't make a difference to the Director.
无论如何 协议已经提出来了
The deal's on the table already, no matter what.
是的 但我和沃伊特一起的时间比你们任何人都长
True, but I've spent more time with Voit than any of you.
他的弱点就是傲慢
His weakness is his hubris.
他觉得自己掌控一切时
That's when he makes a mistake,
就是他犯错的时候
when he thinks he's in charge.
可能是承认 也可能是失误
It could be an admission or a slip- up.
我们需要的是一些能让他进入
What we need is something that pushes him into violence
隐藏暴力状态的东西
that we know is just below the surface.
所以我们和沃伊特相处的时间越多
So the more time we spend with Voit,
我们就有更多机会来惹怒他
the more opportunity we have to get under his skin,
拿到能用来对付他的材料
get ammunition that we can use against him.
没错 我们已经知道他是六眼杀蛛了
Exactly. We already know he's Sicarius.
只需要向全世界证明就行了
We just have to prove it to the world.
所以我们要利用这个案子 来带出这个恶魔
So we need to use this case to bring the monster out,
向局长 向总检查长证明
to the Director, to the Attorney General.
我可以自己往油管上发
Hey, I'll post it on YouTube myself.
我不在乎 关键是 一旦成功
I don't give a fuck. The point is, when it happens,
那什么协议都救不了他了
there's no deal in the world that's going to save his ass.
伊莱亚斯·沃伊特不能出狱
Elias Voit is not getting out of prison.
绝对不行
Never.
好了 谁想先尝试一下
Now, who wants first crack at him?
你不行
And not you.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.